ETHAN FOURNIER

ethanjosephfournier@gmail.com | https://ethanfournier.dev/ | https://github.com/EthanJF

SOFTWARE ENGINEER / FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Creative thinker with experience in React.js, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, and Git. My time as a technical educator allowed me to empathize with the various ways people understand software engineering while also deepening my own technical knowledge and communication skills. My background in project management gave me the tools to work with teams to achieve optimal productivity. I'm passionate about using technology to bring people from diverse demographics together.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, ES6, React.js, Redux.js, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL, Git, GitHub, HTML, CSS

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

OkFriend - Frontend | Backend | Demo | Live

OkCupid but for friends! A place to find, chat, and set up events with friends by area, interest, gender, and age

- Used several self-referential tables in order to create friendships, chats, and calendar invites among users
- Implemented dynamic routing to successfully generate URLs for over 500 users
- Used RandomUser.me as an API to populate internal database with information from random users
- Utilized the zipcodes NPM package to filter users by a certain radius from the current user
- Integrated Ruby's RestClient gem to access data from external APIs
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side

We ♥ Dogs - Frontend | Backend | Demo | Live

Recreated an Instagram-style web application that allowed you to rate and comment on various dog pictures

- Used the Twitter API to access pictures of dogs from various Twitter accounts
- Combined various technologies (Twurl, Ruby) to populate database with pictures of dogs from the Twitter API
- Implemented Fetch in JavaScript to grab pictures of dogs from internal API
- Utilized custom CSS and CSS Grid to recreate Instagram's look and feel
- Used responsive web design that adjusts the user's experience based on their browser size

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Coach, Flatiron School

New York, New York 3/2020 - 2/2021

- Assisted instruction in Ruby, SQL, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript and React JS in cohorts of up to 45 students
- Led review sessions, graded code challenges, and hosted regular office hours to check in with students
- Hand-picked to coach the fellowship cohort, working with the Tech Talent Pipeline to help students from underprivileged communities change their lives and begin a career in tech
- Coaching the fellowship cohort included additional duties such as regularly updating social workers with the technical and emotional progress of 25 students

Process Administrator, Tudor Realty Services Corp

New York, New York 6/2018 - 7/2019

- Streamlined closing process for multiple sales agents with up-to-date software and reviewing sales packages on a daily basis
- Verified application information for lawyers, brokers, and shareholders to ensure accuracy and smooth sales process
- Organized tenant moves among superintendents, shareholders and moving companies

Scheduling Manager, The City Bakery

New York, New York 8/2016 - 3/2018

- Managed schedules for The City Bakery and 6 Birdbath locations, responsible for over 230 shifts weekly
- Resolved scheduling conflicts, published weekly schedules and ensured store managers met weekly deadlines
- Created the schedule for The City Bakery for 20 counter and bussing employees in over 75 shifts per week

Other Experience

- Copyeditor/Copywriter, Self-Employed, Remote, 11/2013 7/2016
- Project Manager, OES-Aidan, Remote (Contract), 3/2013 9/2013

EDUCATION

Flatiron School
Software Engineering Immersive
University of Florida
Bachelor of Science (BS), Journalism

Brooklyn, New York 9/2019 - 1/2020

Gainesville, Florida

8/2012